PANAKORN DEJTHUMRONGWAT

Eight years of experience in management consulting serving clients from MNCs, medium-sized companies, state-owned enterprises and government agencies; mainly focus on retail, FMCG, F&B, manufacturing, telecommunication and public services sectors. Support clients in enter-to-market strategy, market research, business analysis, strategic planning, stakeholder engagement, partner search, M&A, project and performance evaluation and etc.

Currently work for a consulting firm owned by the Swedish government advising Swedish companies on doing business in Southeast Asia and strengthening international relationship with local stakeholders. Have strong network with policymakers and business communities in Southeast Asia and the EU. Graduated from leading Thai and UK universities in political science, economics and public administration.



(+66) 085-100-2631



panakorn777@hotmail.com



Academic Degrees

- Master of Arts in Global Political Economy City University of London, UK
- Bachelor of Arts in Political Science Major: Public Administration, Minor: Economics Thammasat University, Thailand

Certificate

- Business Analysis: Faculty of Economics -Chulalongkorn University
- TQA Criteria: Thailand Productivity Institute
- Economics of Money and Banking: Barnard College - Columbia University's Coursera Course
- Private Equity and Venture Capital: Università Bocconi Coursera Course
- Corporate Strategy: UCL School of Management Coursera Course

WORK EXPERIENCES











Retail

Aut

Telco

Finance

Business Sweden (The Swedish Trade and Invest Council)

Position: Consultant

2016 - Present

- Create enter to market strategy for multinational corporations (MNCs) and SMEs
- Conduct market and competitor analysis, market size estimation and identifying key success factors
- Advise clients on business strategy, performance improvement and finding new revenue stream
- Support client to improve relationship and build trust with local business partners, local governments and key policy makers
- Monitor economic, business and political situation, also provide recommendation to Swedish policymakers

TRIS Corporation

Position: Senior Analyst

2013 - 2016

- Monitor and evaluate project, policy and organization performance
- Research on public policies
- Design corporate strategy
- Implement organization re-structuring plan
- Develop business working process

Double A Alliance

Position: **Acting Human Resource Manager** 2010 – 2011

- Manage tax planning regarding manpower
- Supervise payroll and compensation tasks
- Support recruitment and human resource development

EXAMPLE WORKS

Automotive and public transport

- Support automotive OEMs both passenger car, commercial transport, and solution providers to turnaround business performance and execute business deals both
- Conduct market research, analyse competitors, identify key opportunity, and evaluate dealers' performance
- Approach local governments and influencing policy

Non-alcohol beverage

- Support European beverage producer to enter South East Asia market
- Analyse cost structure, price point and distribution channel for beverage product

• Forestry industry

- Support plantation companies to strengthen relationship with authorities, acquiring land and expand production in South East Asia
- Identify forestry opportunity in Asia Pacific region and manage feasibility study for investment project
- Build relationship between Sweden and Lao PDR regarding forestry industry development

Smart City

- Support innovative solution providers to enter new market and execute business deals with private and public customers
- Identify market opportunities, advise on brand and product positioning, and strengthen relationship with development project owners

Machinery and automation

- Support innovative machinery and solution providers to improve business performance
- Conduct research on market trend and opportunities
- Promote innovative and advanced solution among manufacturers

• <u>M&A</u>

- Support industrial manufacturer and services companies to inorganic growth
- Conduct market analysis and value proposition
- Identify M&A target and support client to execute the deal
- Perform non-financial due diligence

Healthcare

- Support international pharmaceutical and medical devices companies to enter new market and build trust with authorities, KOLs and customers
- Advise client on market situation, trend and business opportunities
- Identify suitable partner for entering to market and accelerate growth
- Conduct stakeholder management, approach key opinion leaders, and create platform for collaboration with policy makers and customers

Venture capital, start-ups and SMEs

- Advise a Thai conglomerates to establish CVC unit
- Support Start-ups companies to accelerate entering to market and venture capitalist to identify investment target and monitor result
- Create evaluation model to identify SMEs' Business persistent and performance analysis for Ministry of Industry

Project and policy monitoring and evaluation

 Conduct project monitoring and evaluation for Ministry of Finance; such as Thai Kem Kang, Development Policy Loan (DPL) and Water Management System and the Country's Future Building (3.5 billion water development project)

Strategic planning

 Draft organization and market strategy for MNCs and SOEs, also supporting on strategic implementation

• Human Rights Due Diligence

- Conduct Human Rights risks assessment in country and industry level
- Advise MNCs to identify Human Rights risks in business operation and draft mitigation plan

International Development Aid

 Support international development institute and government to provide development loan and grant to developing countries